Finding Aid to the Smith College Archives long playing (LP) records collection CA.MS.01116
Smith College Archives
Smith College Archives long playing (LP) records collection
1948-1964
Smith College Archives
CA.MS.01116
6.604 linear feet (7 containers)
The LP collection was created by the Smith College Archives from various sources. The LP collection consists mainly of recorded speeches and musical performances by Smith College individuals and groups. They span the twentieth century.
Conditions Governing Access
Until we move into New Neilson in early 2021, collections are stored in multiple locations and may take up to 48 hours to retrieve. Researchers are strongly encouraged to contact Special Collections (specialcollections@smith.edu) at least a week in advance of any planned visits so that boxes may be retrieved for them in a timely manner.
The records are open to research according to the regulations of the College Archives. Audio cassette copies of the LPs may be ordered for research purposes.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The LP Records were donated over a period of time from a variety of sources.
Arrangement
The collection of LPs are divided according to size – 10", 12" and 16/17".
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
The collection is open to research. However, Smith College Special Collection may not have the equipment to play these LPs. Contact spacial collections staff for more information.
Scope and Contents
The LP collection consists mainly of recorded speeches and musical performances by Smith College individuals and groups. They span the twentieth century. Significant speeches to the college body were often recorded. These could be ceremonial (the inauguration of President Wright; the presentation of an honorary degree to Eleanor Roosevelt) or religious (chapel readings by President Neilson; chapel remarks by Annetta Clark). The voices of college Presidents Seelye, Neilson and Wright can all be found in the LPs. Smith traditions such as Rally Day and Christmas Vespers are also preserved in this collection. More well-known recordings are records by the Smiffenpoofs, Smithereens, and Octavians, three of Smith's a cappella choirs. The Smith College Glee Club, Choir, Chamber Singers, and Chamber Orchestra also made recordings of their concerts that now reside in the archives. Miscellaneous LPs include several International Quizzes that Smith students participated in, and the Smith College 75th Anniversary Fund radio spots.
- 8"/10" Discs
  - Smith College Vespers, 1954; 1 items (Box 8)
  - Edna Williams of Spoken American English [8"], undated; 1 items (Box 8)
  - Edna Williams [6"], undated; 1 items (Box 8)
  - Edna Williams [10"], undated; 1 items (Box 8)
  - Smith College Senior Song/Candidate for New Alma Mater, 1950; 1 items (Box 8)
  - Smith College Glee Club, 1950; 1 items (Box 8)
  - "We're '39" - Smiffenpoofs, 1939; 1 items (Box 8)
  - "Merry Christmas Miss Ainsworth", 1956; 1 items (Box 8)
- 10" Discs
  - 1-2 - Chapel Readings by President William Allan Neilson of Smith College, the 90th Psalm and Proverbs 31, undated; 2 items LP disc (Box 1)
  - 3-5 - Digging Up Bible Life, Dr. Elihu Grant, Robinson Recording Labs, Discs #2-4, 1934-03-28; 3 items LP disc (Box 1)
  - 6 - "We're '39" -- Newt Perry's Orchestra, Smiffenpoofs -- music by Jeanne Perkins, words by Rose Kummel, undated; 1 items LP disc (Box 1)
  - 7 - Inauguration of President Wright -- Part 1, 1949; 1 items LP disc (Box 1)
  - 8-10 - James Bryant Conant -- Parts 1-4, undated; 3 items LP disc (Box 1)
  - 11-13 - Mrs. F.D.R. -- Parts 1-6, undated; 3 items LP disc (Box 1)
  - 14-16 - H.M. Cam -- Parts 1-5 and degree to Mrs. F.D.R., undated; 3 items LP disc (Box 1)
  - 17-18 - G.T. Cori -- Parts 1-4, undated; 2 items LP disc (Box 1)
  - 19-20 - E.C. Morrow -- Parts 1-4, undated; 2 items LP disc (Box 1)
  - 21-22 - M.C. Smith -- Parts 1-4, undated; 2 items LP disc (Box 1)
  - 23 - A.F. Wright - Barbara Ward -- Part 1, undated; 1 items LP disc (Box 1)
  - 24-26 - Barbara Ward -- Parts 3-8, undated; 2 items LP disc (Box 1)
  - 26a - Empty sleeve for "Smith College Sings, 1952-1953; 1 items LP disc (Box 1)
  - 27 - Smiffenpoof Album -- "St. Louis Blues", Mood Indigo", "One, Two, Three, Four", 1944; 1 items (Box 2)
  - 28 - Smiffenpoof Album -- "The Night is Young", "Put a Penny in the Drum", "My Cutie's Due", "Oh What A Man", 1944; 1 items (Box 2)
  - 29 - Smiffenpoof Album -- "My Heart Took a Walk", "Lindy", "Theme", "S'posin'", 1944; 1 items (Box 2)
  - 30 - Vie Universitaire -- Interview d'etudiantes de "Smith College" par Daniel Perrin, 1948-11-12; 1 items (Box 2)
  - 31-32 - Untitled, 1948-11-12; 2 items (Box 2)
  - 33-33a - "The Smith Medley" -- Smithereens; "Handle Me With Care", "Tumblin' Tumbleweed" -- Octavians, 1948-1949; 2 items (Box 2)
  - 34-34a - "Lydia the Tattooed Lady" -- Octavians; "I'm Bidin' My Time, "Happy Cuz I Have You" -- Smithereens, 1948-1949; 2 items (Box 2)
  - 35-35a - "Round Boogie", "Salvation Army Song", "Oh What A Man", "My Cutie's Due" -- Smiffenpoofs, 1948-1949; 2 items (Box 2)
  - 36 - B.F. Wright -- Parts 3-4, 1949; 2 items (Box 2)
  - 38-39 - "Love Among the Ruins" -- Smith Faculty Show, 1952; 2 items (Box 2)
  - 40 - Louise Rood, Viola and Robert Miller, Piano -- Sonatina (Edwin London) and Sonatina in G Minor, Op. 137, No. 3 (Schubert), undated; 1 items (Box 2)
  - 41 - Louise Rood, Viola and Robert Miller, Piano -- Sonata in F (Bach) & Louise Rood, Viola -- Sonata for Viola Alone, Op. 25, No. 1, undated; 1 items (Box 2)
  - 42 - "The Creation" (Haydn) -- Nova Labs, undated; 1 items (Box 2)
  - 43-44 - Smith College Glee Club -- directed by Iva Dee Hait and accompanied by Helen Bilhorn, undated; 2 items (Box 2)
- 12" Discs
  - BOX 3 MISSING (items 1-42)
  - 43-45 - "Mass in B Minor" (Bach) -- Parts 1-6 -- Smith College Glee Club, Amherst College Glee Club, and Five College Chamber Orchestra, undated; 3 items (Box 4)
  - 46 - "Crazy Rhythm" -- Smithereens, undated; 1 items (Box 4)
  - 47 - "Once Was a Time..." -- Smiffenpoofs, undated; 1 items (Box 4)
  - 48 - "Christmas Vespers, 1974" -- Smith College -- Glee Club, Harvard Glee Club, Smith College Choirs, 1 items (Box 4)
  - 49 - "Christmas Vespers, 1975" -- Smith College -- Glee Club, Amherst College Glee Club, Smith College Choirs, 2 items (Box 4)
  - 50 - "Christmas Vespers, 1976" -- Smith College -- Glee Club, Harvard Glee Club, Smith College Choirs, and The Chamber Orchestra, 1 items (Box 4)
  - 51 - "College Choirs at Christmas" -- Amherst College Glee Club, undated; 1 items (Box 4)
  - 52 - "College Choirs at Christmas" -- The Morgan State University, undated; 1 items (Box 4)
  - 53 - "College Choirs at Christmas" -- Smith College Glee Club, undated; 1 items (Box 4)
  - 54 - "Christmas Vespers, 1977" -- Smith College Choirs, 1 items (Box 4)
  - 55 - "Christmas Vespers, 1978" -- Harvard Glee Club and Smith College Choirs, 1 items (Box 4)
  - 56 - "Definitive Smiffenpoofs", undated; 1 items (Box 4)
  - 57 - "Christmas Vespers, 1979" -- Smith College Glee Club and Union College Glee Club, 1 items (Box 4)
  - 58 - "Smithereens' Greatest Hits, Volume II", undated; 1 items (Box 4)
  - 59 - "Christmas Vespers, 1980" -- Glee Club and Choir, Union College Men's Glee Club, Smith College Alpha and Omega Choirs, 1 items (Box 4)
  - 60 - "After the Gold Rush" -- Smiffenpoofs, undated; 1 items (Box 4)
  - 61 - "Christmas Vespers, 1980" -- Smith College Glee Club and Choir, Union College Men's Glee Club, Smith College Alpha and Omega Choirs, 1982; 1 items (Box 4)
  - 62 - "Smiffenpoofs: A Living Jukebox", undated; 1 items (Box 4)
  - ITEMS 63-64 MISSING, N/A; 2 items (Box 4)
  - 65 - Music from the Rally Days of 1951 at Smith College, 2 items (Box 4)
  - 66 - Smith College Rally Day Shows, 1957; 1 items (Box 4)
  - 67-68 - "The Smith College Chamber Singers on Tour", undated; 2 items (Box 4)
  - 69 - Smith College Glee Club, conducted by Robert Brawley; Smith College Octavians, directed by Alice Parker, undated; 1 items (Box 4)
  - 70-72 - Smith College Glee Club, conducted by Robert Brawley -- Parts 3-8, undated; 3 items (Box 4)
  - 73 - "Gardening for Blind Persons" -- The Cleveland Society for the Blind, undated; 1 items (Box 4)
  - 74 - Duplicate of #61, 1982; 1 items (Box 4)
  - 75 - Smith College Christmas Vespers, 1967-12-10; 1 items (Box 4)
  - 76 - Smith College Vespers, 1968; 1 items (Box 4)
  - 77-80 - Opening Dedication of Josten Werner Performing Arts Library, 1968-11-03; 4 items (Box 4)
  - 80a-d - Smith College Faculty Show, 1952; 1 linear feet (Box 5)
  - 81 - Smith College Glee Club and Princeton University Glee Club, 1965-04-11; 1 items (Box 5)
  - 82 - The Smith-Princeton Chamber Chorus in Europe, 1965; 1 items (Box 5)
  - 83 - Smithereens at Smith, 1964; 1 items (Box 5)
  - 84 - The Smith College Choirs, 1963-1964; 1 items (Box 5)
  - 85 - Smiffenpoof Album, 1946; 1 items (Box 5)
  - 86 - Smith College Glee Club with the Harvard Glee Club - 75th Anniversary Concert, 1962; 1 items (Box 5)
  - 87 - "The Smithereens", c. 1960; 1 items (Box 5)
  - 88 - Smith College Glee Club album (containing four records), 1947; 4 items (Box 6)
  - 88a - Empty record sleeve, undated; 1 items (Box 6)
- 16"/17" Discs
  - 90 - Untitled, undated; 1 items (Box 7)
  - 91 - Missa "O quam gloriosum" -- Parts 2-3, undated; 1 items (Box 7)
  - 92 - "Smith College", undated; 1 items (Box 7)
  - 93 - Missa "O quam gloriosum" -- Part 1, undated; 1 items (Box 7)
  - 94 - Smith College Glee Club, 1947; 1 items (Box 7)
  - 95 - "Smith College 75th Anniversary Fund" -- Campaign Drive/Radio Spots, c. 1950; 1 items (Box 7)
  - 96- "New England Colleges: Smith -- Amherst", undated; 1 items (Box 7)
  - 97 - "International Quiz", 1950; 1 items (Box 7)
  - 98-99 - "International Quiz #13 -- Bangor vs. Smith", 1951; 2 items (Box 7)
  - 100-101 - "International Quiz #10 -- Liverpool vs. Smith", 1951; 2 items (Box 7)